<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>AsyncTrigger</title>
<desc>
 The AsyncTrigger class is used to fire an event at the timing of event delivery immediately after control returns to KiriKiri. This function is called an <kw>asynchronous trigger</kw>. <r/>
 In scripts that use an event-driven programming model like KiriKiri, this is useful when you want to perform processing outside of an event handler that cannot be executed within it (for example, trying to invalidate the object that generated the event within that event handler). <r/>
</desc>

<member>
	<name>AsyncTrigger</name>
	<type>constructor</type>
	<shortdesc>Construction of AsyncTrigger object</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>owner</name>
			<default></default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the target for the event. <r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
		<argitem>
			<name>actionname</name>
			<default>"action"</default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the name of the method to receive the event in the target object specified by owner. 
				 If an empty string is specified, owner is treated as a method, and owner is called directly 
				 for each event occurrence. <r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Constructs an AsyncTrigger class object. <r/>
	</desc>
</member>


<member>
	<name>onFire</name>
	<type>event</type>
	<shortdesc>When fired</shortdesc>
	<arg></arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Occurs after the trigger is pulled with the <ref>AsyncTrigger.trigger</ref> method. <r/>
	</desc>
</member>


<member>
	<name>trigger</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Pull the trigger</shortdesc>
	<arg>
	</arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Generates an event. <r/>
		 After calling this method, control returns to the KiriKiri core, and the <ref>AsyncTrigger.onFire</ref> 
		 event occurs when the KiriKiri core reaches the stage of delivering accumulated asynchronous events. <r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>cancel</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Cancel the trigger</shortdesc>
	<arg>
	</arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Cancels the trigger pulled with the <ref>AsyncTrigger.trigger</ref> method. <r/>
		 It can be canceled at any time before firing. <r/>
	</desc>
</member>


<member>
	<name>cached</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Whether to cache events</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Indicates whether to cache events. You can also set the value. <r/>
		 If true is specified, the event will fire only once no matter how many times the 
		 <ref>AsyncTrigger.trigger</ref> method is called before firing. <r/>
		 If false is specified, it will fire as many times as it was called before firing. <r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>mode</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Mode</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Indicates the operation mode. You can also set the value. <r/>
		 Specify one of the following values: <r/>
		<tt><kw>atmNormal</kw>    : </tt> Fired during the normal event delivery stage. <r/>
		<tt><kw>atmExclusive</kw> : </tt> Fired with priority over other asynchronous events. <r/>
		<tt><kw>atmAtIdle</kw>    : </tt> Fired in the idle state (when there are no other events to deliver). <r/>
		 When triggers are pulled at the same time, the firing order is atmExclusive, atmNormal, then atmIdle. <r/>
		 If multiple triggers of the same mode are pulled, they fire in the order they were pulled. <r/>
	</desc>
	<ref>Timer.mode</ref>
</member>

</doc>