<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>Debug</title>
<desc>
 The Debug class provides features related to KiriKiri debugging. You cannot create objects from this class.<r/>
 The KiriKiri console log name is krkr.console.log. Additionally, the file created when a hardware exception occurs is hwexcept.log.<r/>
 These log files are located in the project directory by default. However, they will not be output if the project directory is read-only, such as when it is an archive.<r/>
 The log file output destination can be changed with the logLocation property (in KAG, it is set to the save data location).<r/>
</desc>

<member>
	<name>message</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Outputs a message to the console</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>message</name>
			<default></default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the message to output.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Outputs a message to the <kw>console</kw>.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>notice</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Outputs an important message to the console</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>message</name>
			<default></default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the message to output.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Outputs a message to the <kw>console</kw>.<r/>
		Unlike <ref>Debug.message</ref>, messages output here will always be written to the log file, even if log file writing starts later (messages output with Debug.message are only written back to a certain point). Use this to output important information that would be useful when collecting log files.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>startLogToFile</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Starts console log output to a file</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>clear</name>
			<default>false</default>
			<desc>
				 If true is specified, the log file is cleared.<r/>
				 If false is specified, it is appended to the existing file.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Starts outputting the console log to a file.<r/>
	</desc>
	<ref>Debug.logToFileOnError</ref>
	<ref>Debug.clearLogFileOnError</ref>
</member>

<member>
	<name>logAsError</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Starts log output to a file in the same way as when an error occurs</shortdesc>
	<arg>
	</arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Performs the same action as when KiriKiri encounters an error regarding the error log file.
		That is, if <ref>Debug.logToFileOnError</ref> is true, it starts outputting the console log to a file.
		At that time, if <ref>Debug.clearLogFileOnError</ref> is true, the file is cleared.<r/>
		In contrast, <ref>Debug.startLogToFile</ref> unconditionally starts outputting the console log to a file.<r/>
	</desc>
	<ref>Debug.startLogToFile</ref>
	<ref>Debug.logToFileOnError</ref>
	<ref>Debug.clearLogFileOnError</ref>
</member>

<member>
	<name>addLoggingHandler</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Adds a logging handler</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>handler</name>
			<default></default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the logging handler.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Registers a handler to be called every time an error log is output.<r/>
		 The handler is called with the log message as an argument.<r/>
		 Even if a log is output within the registered method, recursive calls are not made and are ignored.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>removeLoggingHandler</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Removes a logging handler</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>handler</name>
			<default></default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the logging handler.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Removes the registered logging handler.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>getLastLog</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Retrieves un-output logs</shortdesc>
	<arg>
	</arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Retrieves logs that have not been output.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>logLocation</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Log file output destination</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Represents the output destination directory for log files. You can also write a value to it.<r/>
		 By default, it is set to the data storage location (command line option -datapath).<r/>
		 Changing this value will cause subsequent logs to be output as *.console.log under that directory.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>logToFileOnError</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Whether to output the console log to a file when an error occurs</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 If true, console log output to a file will start when an error occurs.<r/>
		 If false, log output to a file will not start even if an error occurs.<r/>
	</desc>
	<ref>Debug.startLogToFile</ref>
	<ref>Debug.clearLogFileOnError</ref>
</member>

<member>
	<name>clearLogFileOnError</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Whether to clear the console log file when an error occurs</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 If true, the console log will be automatically cleared when an error occurs.<r/>
		 If false, it will not be cleared and will be appended to the existing log file.<r/>
	</desc>
	<ref>Debug.startLogToFile</ref>
	<ref>Debug.logToFileOnError</ref>
</member>


</doc>