<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>Font</title>
<desc>
 The Font class is a class for managing <kw>fonts</kw>.<r/>
</desc>



<member>
	<name>getTextWidth</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Get the width of a string</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>text</name>
			<default></default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the string for which you want to get the width.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result>Returns the width of the specified string in pixels</result>
	<desc>
		 This method allows you to get the width required when drawing the specified string 
		 with the current font settings.<r/>
	</desc>
	<ref>Font.getTextHeight</ref>
</member>

<member>
	<name>getTextHeight</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Get the height of a string</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>text</name>
			<default></default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the string for which you want to get the height.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result>Returns the height of the specified string in pixels</result>
	<desc>
		 This method allows you to get the height required when drawing the specified string with this font.<r/>
	</desc>
	<ref>Font.getTextWidth</ref>
</member>

<member>
	<name>getEscWidthX</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>X-coordinate movement amount in the horizontal direction of the character</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>text</name>
			<default></default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the string for which you want to get the X-coordinate movement amount in the horizontal direction.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result>Returns the X-coordinate movement amount in the horizontal direction in pixels</result>
	<desc>
		 You can get the movement amount of the character drawing position required when drawing 
		 the specified character with the current font settings.<r/>
		 This method allows you to get the movement amount on the X-coordinate when moving 
		 horizontally (left) relative to the character drawing direction.<r/>
	</desc>
	<ref>Font.getEscWidthY</ref>
	<ref>Font.getEscHeightX</ref>
	<ref>Font.getEscHeightY</ref>
</member>

<member>
	<name>getEscWidthY</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Y-coordinate movement amount in the horizontal direction of the character</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>text</name>
			<default></default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the string for which you want to get the Y-coordinate movement amount in the horizontal direction.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result>Returns the Y-coordinate movement amount in the horizontal direction in pixels</result>
	<desc>
		 You can get the movement amount of the character drawing position required when drawing 
		 the specified character with the current font settings.<r/>
		 This method allows you to get the movement amount on the Y-coordinate when moving 
		 horizontally (left) relative to the character drawing direction.<r/>
	</desc>
	<ref>Font.getEscWidthX</ref>
	<ref>Font.getEscHeightX</ref>
	<ref>Font.getEscHeightY</ref>
</member>

<member>
	<name>getEscHeightX</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>X-coordinate movement amount in the vertical direction of the character</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>text</name>
			<default></default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the string for which you want to get the X-coordinate movement amount in the vertical direction.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result>Returns the X-coordinate movement amount in the vertical direction in pixels</result>
	<desc>
		 You can get the movement amount of the character drawing position required when drawing 
		 the specified character with the current font settings.<r/>
		 This method allows you to get the movement amount on the X-coordinate when moving 
		 vertically (down) relative to the character drawing direction.<r/>
	</desc>
	<ref>Font.getEscWidthX</ref>
	<ref>Font.getEscWidthY</ref>
	<ref>Font.getEscHeightY</ref>
</member>

<member>
	<name>getEscHeightY</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Y-coordinate movement amount in the vertical direction of the character</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>text</name>
			<default></default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the string for which you want to get the Y-coordinate movement amount in the vertical direction.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result>Returns the Y-coordinate movement amount in the vertical direction in pixels</result>
	<desc>
		 You can get the movement amount of the character drawing position required when drawing 
		 the specified character with the current font settings.<r/>
		 This method allows you to get the movement amount on the Y-coordinate when moving 
		 vertically (down) relative to the character drawing direction.<r/>
	</desc>
	<ref>Font.getEscWidthX</ref>
	<ref>Font.getEscWidthY</ref>
	<ref>Font.getEscHeightX</ref>
</member>

<member>
	<name>getGlyphDrawRect</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Actual drawing range of the string</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>text</name>
			<default></default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the string for which you want to get the range.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result>Actual drawing range of the string</result>
	<desc>
		 You can get the range where the glyph image is drawn when drawing the specified character with the current font settings.<r/>
		 The obtained range is a Rect class object based on the 0,0 coordinates.<r/>
		 Only horizontal orientation is supported.<r/>
	</desc>
	<ref>Rect</ref>
</member>

<member>
	<name>getList</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Enumeration of font names</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>flags</name>
			<default></default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies how to enumerate fonts.<r/>
				 Specify a combination of the following values using bitwise OR.<r/>
				<tt><kw>fsfFixedPitch</kw>    </tt> : Enumerates only fixed-pitch fonts<r/>
				<tt><kw>fsfSameCharSet</kw>   </tt> : Enumerates only fonts with the same character set<r/>
				<tt><kw>fsfNoVertical</kw>    </tt> : Does not enumerate vertical writing fonts<r/>
				<tt><kw>fsfTrueTypeOnly</kw>  </tt> : Enumerates only TrueType fonts<r/>
				<tt><kw>fsfIgnoreSymbol</kw>  </tt> : Excludes symbol character sets<r/>
				 If fsfSameCharSet is specified, fonts with the same character set as the 
				 currently selected font will be enumerated.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result>An array where each element is a font name (string)</result>
	<desc>
		Enumerates font names and returns them as an array.
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>mapPrerenderedFont</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Mapping of pre-rendered fonts</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>fontstorage</name>
			<default></default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the pre-rendered font storage.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Maps a <kw>pre-rendered font</kw> to the currently selected font name.<r/>
		 From then on, the specified pre-rendered font will be used instead for fonts with the same settings.<r/>
		 The setting becomes effective for all layers.<r/>
	</desc>
	<ref>Font.unmapPrerenderedFont</ref>
</member>

<member>
	<name>unmapPrerenderedFont</name>
	<type>method</type>
	<shortdesc>Unmapping of pre-rendered fonts</shortdesc>
	<arg>
	</arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Unmaps the <kw>pre-rendered font</kw> for the currently selected font name.<r/>
	</desc>
	<ref>Font.mapPrerenderedFont</ref>
</member>


<member>
	<name>face</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Font name</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Represents the font name. You can also set a value.<r/>
		 Multiple candidates can be specified separated by commas. In this case, an actually existing font is used, with priority given to those listed first. Whether a font actually exists is determined by referring to the OS font list. If none of the candidates match, the default font is used (fixed to "MS PGothic" in the current version).<r/>
		 If you start with a comma followed by a font name, it will attempt to specify that font to the OS even if the OS does not enumerate it (e.g., ",My Original Font"). This allows the use of non-enumerable fonts registered with the AddFontResource Win32 API, etc.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>height</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Font height</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Represents the height of the drawn characters in pixels. You can also set a value.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>bold</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Bold</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Indicates whether the font is bold. You can also set a value.<r/>
		 If true is specified, it becomes bold.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>italic</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Italic</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Indicates whether the font is italic. You can also set a value.<r/>
		 If true is specified, it becomes italic.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>strikeout</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Strikeout</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Indicates whether to draw a strikeout line. You can also set a value.<r/>
		 If true is specified, a strikeout line is drawn over the characters.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>underline</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Underline</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Indicates whether to draw an underline. You can also set a value.<r/>
		 If true is specified, an underline is drawn.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>angle</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Character drawing angle</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Represents the character drawing angle. You can also set a value.<r/>
		 The unit is 10 times the value in degrees. It takes a value from 0 to 3600.<r/>
		 When performing vertical writing, specify a vertical writing font name for the font name 
		 and set this property to 2700.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>rasterizer</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>String rendering method</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Represents the string rendering method. You can also set a value.<r/>
		 Specify one of the following values.<r/>
		<tt><kw>frGDI</kw>      </tt> : Draws characters using GDI<r/>
		<tt><kw>frFreeType</kw> </tt> : Draws characters using FreeType<r/>
		If FreeType is specified, only horizontal writing is supported. Others are not supported.<r/>
		This property is static. Set the value using Font.rasterizer.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

</doc>