<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>Timer</title>
<desc>
 The Timer class is a class for generating events at regular intervals.<r/>
</desc>

<member>
	<name>Timer</name>
	<type>constructor</type>
	<shortdesc>Construction of a Timer object</shortdesc>
	<arg>
		<argitem>
			<name>owner</name>
			<default></default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the target for event generation.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
		<argitem>
			<name>actionname</name>
			<default>"action"</default>
			<desc>
				 Specifies the name of the method to receive events in the object specified by owner.
				If an empty string is specified, owner is treated as a method, and owner is called
				directly at each event interval.<r/>
			</desc>
		</argitem>
	</arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Constructs a Timer class object.<r/>
		 In the initial state, the interval property is 1000 and the enabled property is false.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>


<member>
	<name>onTimer</name>
	<type>event</type>
	<shortdesc>Timer interval reached</shortdesc>
	<arg></arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Called at each timer interval.
	</desc>
</member>



<member>
	<name>interval</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Event generation interval</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Represents the event generation <kw>interval</kw>. You can also set the value.<r/>
		 The unit is ms (milliseconds), and events occur at the specified time intervals.<r/>
		 You can also specify the interval as a real number. In the current version, it can be
		specified with a precision of 1/65536 milliseconds (values after the decimal point are
		rounded to this precision).<r/>
		 Even though it has a precision of about 1/65536 milliseconds, there is no guarantee that
		the event handler will actually be called with this precision. In practice, there is a
		fluctuation of about 3 to 10 ms in the timing of event calls. However, in the average and
		long term, adjustments are automatically made so that events occur at the interval
		specified by this property.
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>capacity</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Maximum allowable event generation capacity</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Specifies how many events can be generated at one time. You can also set the value.<r/>
		 There may be cases where timer events cannot be fully processed, such as when processing
		takes longer than the timer interval. In this case, the timer stores events in the event
		queue, but there is an upper limit to the number of events that can be stored in that
		event queue. This property specifies that maximum number.<r/>
		 When it comes time to process events, Kirikiri attempts to process the number of events
		accumulated in the queue at once.<r/>
		 If 1 is specified, a maximum of only 1 event will accumulate in the event queue. If 0 is
		specified, there is no limit to the number of events that can accumulate in the event queue,
		but be careful as the system may appear to freeze if too many events accumulate.<r/>
		 The default is 6.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>enabled</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Whether to generate events</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Indicates whether to generate events. You can also set the value.<r/>
		 If true, events will occur. If false, events will not occur.
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>mode</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Mode</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Represents the operation mode. You can also set the value.<r/>
		 Specify one of the following values.<r/>
		<tt><kw>atmNormal</kw>    : </tt> Events are delivered with normal event delivery priority.<r/>
		<tt><kw>atmExclusive</kw> : </tt> Delivered with priority over other asynchronous events.<r/>
		<tt><kw>atmAtIdle</kw>    : </tt> Delivered in the idle state (when there are no other events to deliver).<r/>
	</desc>
	<ref>AsyncTrigger.mode</ref>
</member>

</doc>