<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>WaveSoundBuffer.PhaseVocoder</title>
<desc>
 The WaveSoundBuffer.PhaseVocoder class is a filter used by registering this instance in <ref>WaveSoundBuffer.filters</ref>, providing Phase Vocoder functionality.<r/>
 With Phase Vocoder, you can change the pitch while maintaining the playback speed (pitch shifter) or change the playback speed while maintaining the pitch (time shifter).<r/>
</desc>


<member>
	<name>PhaseVocoder</name>
	<type>constructor</type>
	<shortdesc>Construction of PhaseVocoder object</shortdesc>
	<arg>
	</arg>
	<result></result>
	<desc>
		 Constructs a WaveSoundBuffer.PhaseVocoder class object.<r/>
		 Register the created instance to a WaveSoundBuffer instance via <ref>WaveSoundBuffer.filters</ref>.
	</desc>
</member>


<member>
	<name>interface</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Get the interface object</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Used internally. Do not use from scripts.
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>time</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Scale along the time axis</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Represents the scale along the time axis. You can also set the value.<r/>
		 The specifiable value is a real number greater than 0. However, very small values increase CPU load, and in the worst case, playback may not be possible. Also, sound quality deteriorates beyond approximately 1.95, and it may not be possible to improve sound quality even by increasing overlap (due to characteristics of the internal algorithm).<r/>
		 Specifying 1.0 does not change the scale along the time axis (playback speed does not change).<r/>
		 For example, specifying 1.5 increases the time axis scale by 1.5 times, resulting in slower playback (it will take 1.5 times longer to play).<r/>
		 For example, specifying 0.5 decreases the time axis scale by 0.5 times, resulting in faster playback (played at double speed).
		 Even if both the time and pitch properties are 1, the Phase Vocoder filter still operates, slightly degrading sound quality and consuming CPU time. If you intend to use both at 1, it is better to remove this filter from the filter array.<r/>
		 Changes to this property are reflected in real-time, but due to buffering, it takes about 2 seconds before it is actually played. Also, noise may occur during the transition.
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>pitch</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Scale along the frequency axis</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Represents the scale along the frequency axis. You can also set the value.<r/>
		 The specifiable value is a number greater than 0.0.<r/>
		 Specifying 1.0 does not change the scale along the frequency axis (pitch does not change).<r/>
		 For example, specifying 1.0594630943593 raises the pitch by one semitone.<r/>
		 For example, 0.9438743126817 lowers the pitch by one semitone.<r/>
		 Even if both the time and pitch properties are 1, the Phase Vocoder filter still operates, slightly degrading sound quality and consuming CPU time. If you intend to use both at 1, it is better to remove this filter from the filter array.<r/>
		 Changes to this property are reflected in real-time, but due to buffering, it takes about 2 seconds before it is actually played.
	</desc>
</member>


<member>
	<name>window</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Window size</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Represents the window size (frame size) of the FFT (Fast Fourier Transform) used internally by PhaseVocoder.
		 Specify a power of 2 between 64 and 32768. The default is 4096.<r/>
		 Increasing this value improves frequency resolution (making pitch more accurate) but lowers time resolution (making sound attacks duller).<r/>
		 Increasing the value uses more CPU. Find the lowest value that does not degrade sound quality.<r/>
		 For 44.1KHz voice, a window size of about 256 is recommended. For music, a window size of about 4096 is recommended.<r/>
		 Changes to this property are reflected when the <ref>WaveSoundBuffer.open</ref> method is executed.<r/>
	</desc>
</member>

<member>
	<name>overlap</name>
	<type>property</type>
	<shortdesc>Overlap count</shortdesc>
	<access>r/w</access>
	<desc>
		 Represents the overlap count (oversampling factor).<r/>
		 Specify 0 or a power of 2 between 2 and 32. The default is 0.<r/>
		 Specifying 0 sets an appropriate value according to the current time property value.<r/>
		 Increasing this value improves time resolution. It is recommended to use a higher value especially when slowing down the playback speed.<r/>
		 Increasing the value uses more CPU.<r/>
		 Changes to this property are reflected in real-time, but due to buffering, it takes about 2 seconds before it is actually played. Also, noise may occur during the transition.
	</desc>
</member>


</doc>