<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>KiriKiri Settings</title>

<para>
<ptitle>About KiriKiri Settings</ptitle>
 "KiriKiri Settings" is a tool that allows you to configure KiriKiri options via a GUI.<r/>
 It exists to allow end users (secondary users) to perform a certain degree of troubleshooting and performance adjustment themselves.<r/>
 The engine settings are launched by adding -userconf to the KiriKiri executable file.<r/>
<r/>
 Option names, configurable values, and option descriptions use information built into the KiriKiri core.<r/>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>About Configuration Files</ptitle>
 There are two types of KiriKiri configuration files. One is placed in the same location as the KiriKiri executable with the extension changed to <kw>cf</kw>, and the other is placed in the data storage location specified by -datapath in <link href="CommandLine"/> with the extension changed to <kw>cfu</kw>.<r/>
 The .cfu file is generated by the "Engine Configuration (-userconf)" for end users.<r/>
 When settings are configured with the Releaser, a .cf file is created. Please note that the configured options will not be applied unless this file is distributed along with the KiriKiri core.<r/>
 If these files do not exist, they will be created when the engine configuration is launched and the OK button is pressed.<r/>
<note>
Inside the configuration file, entries are listed line by line as "name=\"value\"". The "value" part consists of a sequence of \xNN, where each represents a Unicode code point value. For example, if it is written as opt="\x61\x62\x63\x3042\x3044\x3046", this represents "abc" followed by Japanese characters. Please be careful when writing to these files from other applications.<r/>
Note that if you write it without using the \xNN format, such as opt="abc[Japanese text]", the KiriKiri core can recognize it correctly, but the engine configuration tool may not recognize this format and might not behave as expected. Double quotes on both sides of the value are also required.
</note>
</para>


<para>
<ptitle>Engine Configuration Screen</ptitle>
 The engine configuration screen looks like this:<r/>
<r/>
<img src="Configure.png"/><r/>
<r/>
<dl>
<dt>"Option Name"</dt>
<dd>
 A list of configurable options is displayed.<r/>
 Please also refer to <link href="CommandLine"/>.
</dd>

<dt>"Option Value"</dt>
<dd>
 A list of values that can be set for the option selected in "Option Name" is displayed.<r/>
 Please select one.
</dd>

<dt>"Option Description"</dt>
<dd>
 A description for the option selected in "Option Name" is displayed.
</dd>

</dl>
</para>


</doc>