<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>Copyright, etc.</title>

<para>
<ptitle>Copyright/License</ptitle>
 Please refer to license.txt included with the SDK.<r/>
 The following are FAQs regarding copyright and licenses, or things many people might wonder about.<r/>
 The principles are as written in license.txt, so please be sure to read license.txt.<r/>
 If there is a discrepancy between what is written here and what is written in license.txt, the contents of license.txt shall take precedence.<r/>
<r/>
<dl>
<dt>Do I have to pay the author of Kirikiri...</dt>
<dd>
 There is no need for that.
</dd>

<dt>I want to use it commercially (including shareware)...</dt>
<dd>
 It can be used commercially.<r/>
 Even for commercial use, no license fees are required. It can be used free of charge.
</dd>

<dt>I would like to use your name in my work...</dt>
<dd>
 There is no specific requirement to state in your documentation that you used Kirikiri.<r/>
 Of course, you are welcome to do so (^^;<r/>
 Unless otherwise specified, the license display shown with -about cannot be removed.<r/>
 If you include the license notice in your documentation according to the Modified BSD License, it is possible to remove the license display shown with -about.
</dd>

<dt>Do I have to notify the author of Kirikiri when the work is completed...</dt>
<dd>
 There is no obligation to notify that you used Kirikiri. There is no obligation to notify even in the case of commercial use.<r/>
 However, I would be happy if you could let me know.
</dd>

<dt>I want to use the Kirikiri source code...</dt>
<dd>
 Kirikiri Z is under the Modified BSD License. You can use the source code according to the Modified BSD License.
</dd>
</dl>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>Acknowledgments</ptitle>
 Kirikiri 2 and Kirikiri Z are made possible by the cooperation of many people. We would like to thank everyone for their kindness.<r/>
 In particular, we received a lot of advice from Second Lieutenant PIA regarding Kirikiri/KAG. Thank you very much.<r/>
<r/>
 Kirikiri Z was developed through crowdfunding with the financial support of many people.<r/>
 The people who supported us (in no particular order, titles omitted) are: W.Dee, casper, MCF Co., Ltd., Biscrat, Aoneko, nagai, Lou, Masayuki Takagiwa, Eigo, Yunyun Tantei, Ryogo (Ano Hoshi, now gone), AZ-UME, Akito Kyo, Katsumasa Tsuneyoshi, Jun Koike, miahmie, Circle Baku, Azanashi, Hasshy, Tananaka Seisakusho, Waffle, Wamsoft, TYPE-MOON, and M2 Co., Ltd.<r/>
<r/>
 Various plugins, including the Win32Ole plugin, were provided by Mr. Go Watanabe. Thank you very much.<r/>
<r/>
 The Photoshop-compatible blend functions were provided by Mr. Kenjo. Thank you very much.<r/>
<r/>
 The gamepad support code was provided by Mr. Kiyobee. Thank you very much.<r/>
<r/>
 The documentation for the KAGParser class and KAG extensions were provided by Mr. Kouhei Yanagita. Thank you very much.<r />
<r/>
 The Kirikiri icon was created by Mr. MIK. Thank you very much.<r/>
<r/>
 Various movie playback functions, such as movie playback via layers, incorporate the "Movie Extension" by Mr. Takenori Imoto. Thank you very much.<r/>
<at target="_top" href="http://www.kaede-software.com/">http://www.kaede-software.com/</at><r/>
<r/>
 The blur implementation is based on code provided by Mr. yun. Thank you very much.<r/>
<r/>
 Mr. mey provided patches for Pad-related functional enhancements and implementations such as String.reverse(). Thank you very much.<r/>
<r/>
 The following is a list of programming libraries/support software used by Kirikiri (in no particular order, titles omitted). We are grateful to those who have released these useful libraries.<r/>
<r/>
<dl>
<dt>IJG JPEG Library (Independent JPEG Group)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.ijg.org/">http://www.ijg.org/</at><r/>
    This software is based in part on the work of the Independent JPEG Group.
</dd>

<dt>libpng (Guy Eric Schalnat, Andreas Dilger, Glenn Randers-Pehrson,  and others)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.libpng.org/pub/png/libpng.html">http://www.libpng.org/pub/png/libpng.html</at>
</dd>

<dt>zlib (Jean-loup Gailly, Mark Adler)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.gzip.org/zlib/">http://www.gzip.org/zlib/</at>
</dd>

<dt>ERINA-Library (L.Entis)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.entis.jp/eri/">http://www.entis.jp/eri/</at><r/>
    ERINA-Library Copyright (C) 2001 Leshade Entis, Entis-soft.
</dd>

<dt>Regex++ (Dr John Maddock)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://ourworld.compuserve.com/homepages/John_Maddock/regexpp.htm">http://ourworld.compuserve.com/homepages/John_Maddock/regexpp.htm</at><r/>
    Regex++ Copyright (c) 1998-2000 Dr John Maddock
</dd>

<dt>UPX (Markus F.X.J. Oberhumer &amp; Laszlo Molnar)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://upx.sourceforge.net/">http://upx.sourceforge.net/</at>
</dd>

<dt>Shell Component Library (Takashi Ito)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.bekkoame.ne.jp/~itotaka/">http://www.bekkoame.ne.jp/~itotaka/</at>
</dd>

<dt>NASM, The Netwide Assembler (Simon Tatham, Julian Hall and others)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://nasm.sourceforge.net/">http://nasm.sourceforge.net/</at>
</dd>

<dt>alink (Anthony A.J. Williams)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://alink.home.dhs.org/">http://alink.home.dhs.org/</at>
</dd>

<dt>md5.c (L. Peter Deutsch)</dt>
<dd>
    Copyright (C) 1999, 2000, 2002 Aladdin Enterprises.  All rights reserved.
</dd>

<dt>libogg/libvorbis (Xiph.Org Foundation)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.xiph.org/">http://www.xiph.org/</at><r/>
    <r/>
Copyright (c) 2002, Xiph.org Foundation<r/>
<r/>
Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
are met:<r/>
<r/>
- Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.<r/>
<r/>
- Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright
notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the
documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.<r/>
<r/>
- Neither the name of the Xiph.org Foundation nor the names of its
contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from
this software without specific prior written permission.<r/>
<r/>
THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS
``AS IS'' AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT
LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR
A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE REGENTS OR
CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL,
EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO,
PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR
PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING
NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS
SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
</dd>


<dt>Ogg Vorbis Acceleration Project</dt>
<dd>
Kirikiri 2 uses the SSE-compatible FFT calculation code released by blacksword's Ogg Vorbis Acceleration Project inside the Phase Vocoder.
<at target="_top" href="http://homepage3.nifty.com/blacksword/">http://homepage3.nifty.com/blacksword/</at><r/>
</dd>

<dt>A C-program for MT19937 (Makoto Matsumoto and Takuji Nishimura)</dt>
<dd>
    <at target="_top"  href="http://www.math.keio.ac.jp/matumoto/emt.html">http://www.math.keio.ac.jp/matumoto/emt.html</at><r/>
    <r/>
Copyright (C) 1997 - 2002, Makoto Matsumoto and Takuji Nishimura,
   All rights reserved.     <r/>

Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
are met:<r/>
<ol>
<li> Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.</li>

<li> Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright
notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the
documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.</li>

<li> The names of its contributors may not be used to endorse or promote 
products derived from this software without specific prior written 
permission.</li>
</ol>

THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS
"AS IS" AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT
LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR
A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT OWNER OR
CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL,
EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO,
PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR
PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT