<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>File Corruption Check Tool</title>

<para>
<ptitle>About the File Corruption Check Tool</ptitle>
 Data can become <kw>corrupted</kw> due to issues during installation or computer malfunctions after installation.<r/>
 The "File Corruption Check Tool" is a tool for detecting such "corrupted" files.<r/>
<r/>
 To detect file corruption, you must first sign the distribution files using the <link href="SignTool"/>.<r/>
 The File Corruption Check Tool also verifies the validity of those <kw>digital signatures</kw> (files whose validity cannot be confirmed are treated as "corrupted" by this tool).<r/>
 The files subject to checking are those within the folder where this File Corruption Check Tool is located (it also searches subfolders). Therefore, please place this tool in the installation folder.<r/>
 This tool only checks files that have been signed; it does not check unsigned files. However, as an exception, the KiriKiri core (and executables created with Releaser) will always have their signatures checked, so please ensure the KiriKiri core is signed.<r/>
<note>
The File Corruption Check Tool can detect file corruption, but it cannot detect the "file does not exist" state by itself.<r />
If you suspect missing files are the cause of an error, you can use the "Copy Results" button to copy the list of checked files to the clipboard. You can then have the end user send this list to you for investigation.<r />
</note>

</para>


<para>
<ptitle>File Corruption Check Tool Configuration File</ptitle>
 The main executable for the File Corruption Check Tool is "File Corruption Check Tool.exe" located in the enduser-tools folder, and its configuration file is "File Corruption Check Tool.ini".<r/>
 You must write the settings for the tool here and distribute it along with the main executable.<r/>
<note>
 If you change the name of "File Corruption Check Tool.exe", please change the name of the configuration file as well. For example, if you rename it to "Signature Verification Tool.exe", the configuration file should be "Signature Verification Tool.ini".
</note>
The following items can be configured.<r/>

<dl>
<dt>[message] section - notice</dt>
<dd>
 Specifies the message to be displayed at the top of the screen.<r/>
 The line starting with notice= must be written as a single line (without line breaks), but you can insert a line break by writing [cr].
</dd>

<dt>[message] section - caption</dt>
<dd>
 Specifies the string to be displayed in the window's title bar.<r/>
</dd>

<dt>[key] section - publickey</dt>
<dd>
 Specifies the <kw>public key</kw> used to verify digital signatures.<r/>
 Copy and paste the public key directly here (without writing anything like 'setting name=').<r/>
</dd>

</dl>
 For an example, please refer to the standard "File Corruption Check Tool.ini" (included in the KiriKiri 2 SDK distribution files).
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>Usage</ptitle>
<r/>
 When you launch File Corruption Check Tool.exe, the following screen will be displayed.<r/>
<img src="sigchk.png"/><r/><r/>
<r/>
<dl>
<dt>File List</dt>
<dd>
 Displays a list of files to be checked.<r/>
 The "Status" column will show "Checking", "Unchecked", "Normal", or "Corrupted".<r/>
 If a file is corrupted, it will be displayed as "Corrupted".<r/>
</dd>

<dt>Check</dt>
<dd>
 Starts the check.<r/>
 Checking large files may take some time.
</dd>

<dt>Copy Results</dt>
<dd>
 Copies the results to the clipboard.<r />
 This is useful for having end users send their check results.<r />
 Once the check is complete, the button becomes enabled.<r/>
 The results are tab-separated data, containing (from left to right) the filename, file date, file size, and check result.<r/>
 Additionally, a list of all files and directories within the target directory is copied. If there is a possibility of unexpected files existing, you can check this output.<r/>
</dd>

<dt>Close</dt>
<dd>
Closes the window.
</dd>
</dl>

</para>


</doc>