<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>File/Folder List</title>

<para>
<ptitle>File/Folder List</ptitle>
This section explains files and folders related to Kirikiri.<r/>
This is not an exhaustive list of all files. It focuses on files that require special attention. Please refer to readme.txt for the folder structure of the Kirikiri Z SDK distribution archive.<r/>
For convenience, files related to KAG are also listed.<r/>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>Folders</ptitle>
<dl>
  <dt><kw>plugin</kw> and <kw>plugin64</kw></dt>
  <dd>Folders where Kirikiri looks for plugins. If these folders exist in the same directory as the Kirikiri executable, Kirikiri will reference the plugins placed inside them. -> <link href="Plugins"/></dd>

  <dt><kw>data</kw> and <kw>content-data</kw></dt>
  <dd>If these folders exist in the same directory as the Kirikiri executable, it will treat the folder as the project folder and execute it. -> <link href="Startup"/></dd>

</dl>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>Files</ptitle>
<dl>
  <dt>*.<kw>xp3</kw></dt>
  <dd>Archive files for Kirikiri. -> <link href="Releaser"/></dd>

  <dt><kw>data.xp3</kw> and <kw>data.exe</kw></dt>
  <dd>If these files are in the same folder as the Kirikiri executable, Kirikiri treats them as the project folder and executes them. -> <link href="Startup"/></dd>

  <dt>*.<kw>tpm</kw></dt>
  <dd>Plugins for Kirikiri that are automatically loaded at startup. -> <link href="Plugins"/></dd>

  <dt><kw>krdevui.dll</kw></dt>
  <dd>A DLL used in common by Kirikiri development tools. You do not need to include this file in distributions for end users.</dd>

  <dt><kw>krmovie.dll</kw></dt>
  <dd>Required when playing WMV/MPG in Kirikiri. If you do not perform video playback, you do not need to include this in distributions for end users. -> <at href="f_VideoOverlay.html">VideoOverlay Class</at></dd>

  <dt>*.<kw>dll</kw></dt>
  <dd>In the case of plugins for Kirikiri, they must be included in distributions for end users. Of course, you do not need to include plugins that are not required. -> <link href="Plugins"/></dd>

  <dt><kw>krkr.eXe</kw></dt>
  <dd>The Kirikiri core. You may change the filename when distributing to end users.</dd>

  <dt>*.<kw>cf</kw> and *.<kw>cfu</kw></dt>
  <dd>Files containing options for the Kirikiri core. To enable options specified in "Kirikiri Configuration" (-userconf) (which includes -datapath option specifications, etc.), these must also be included in distributions for end users. -> <link href="Configure"/></dd>

  <dt><kw>FileCorruptionCheckTool.exe</kw> and its .<kw>ini</kw> file</dt>
  <dd>A file corruption check tool. You may change the filename when distributing to end users, but in that case, both the .exe and .ini files must have the same name. In the Kirikiri Z SDK distribution, it is located in enduser-tools, but when distributing to end users, it usually needs to be placed in the same folder as the Kirikiri executable. -> <link href="FileChkTool"/></dd>

  <dt><kw>startup.tjs</kw></dt>
  <dd>A TJS script file. Kirikiri looks for this file directly under the project folder and executes it first. -> <link href="Startup"/></dd>

  <dt>*.<kw>tjs</kw></dt>
  <dd>TJS script files.</dd>

  <dt><kw>msgmap.tjs</kw></dt>
  <dd>A message map file. If you do not recall creating one, you do not need to include this file in distributions for end users. -> <link href="Controller"/></dd>

  <dt>*.<kw>sig</kw></dt>
  <dd>Signature files output by the Key/Signature Tool. These are referenced by tools like the File Corruption Check Tool. -> <link href="SignTool"/></dd>

  <dt>*.<kw>rpf</kw></dt>
  <dd>Releaser profiles. These record Releaser configuration information. You do not need to include these files in distributions for end users (Releaser excludes these files automatically). -> <link href="Releaser"/></dd>

  <dt><kw>hwexcept.log</kw></dt>
  <dd>This may be created at the location specified by the -datapath option when the Kirikiri core crashes. While there are various types of crashes, if this file is created, it indicates a severe crash; please collect it from the end user and send it to the Kirikiri author if necessary. You do not need to include this file in distributions for end users.</dd>

  <dt>*.<kw>console.log</kw></dt>
  <dd>Kirikiri console log files. These may be created at the location specified by the -datapath option, typically when Kirikiri crashes. In most cases, the logs recorded in these files are caused by script syntax errors. Use these to help with debugging during application development or by collecting them from end users after distribution. You do not need to include these files in distributions for end users.</dd>

  <dt>*.<kw>dump.txt</kw></dt>
  <dd>TJS dump files. You do not need to include these files in distributions for end users. -> <link href="Controller"/></dd>

  <dt>*.<kw>sli</kw></dt>
  <dd>Loop definition files output by the Loop Tuner. -> <link href="LoopTuner"/></dd>

  <dt>*.<kw>tft</kw></dt>
  <dd>Rendered font data output by the Rendered Font Data Creation Tool. -> <link href="FontMaker"/></dd>

  <dt>*.png *.jpeg *.jpg *.tlg *.bmp *.jxr</dt>
  <dd>Image files. -> <link href="GraphicSystem"/></dd>

  <dt>*.wav *.tcw *.ogg *.opus</dt>
  <dd>Audio files. -> <link href="SoundSystem"/></dd>

  <dt>*.wmv *.mpg *.mp4 *.ogv</dt>
  <dd>Video files. -> <at href="f_VideoOverlay.html">VideoOverlay Class</at></dd>

  <dt>*.ks</dt>
  <dd>KAG scenario files.</dd>

  <dt>*.ksd *.kdt</dt>
  <dd>KAG save data.</dd>

  <dt>*.asd</dt>
  <dd>KAG animation definition files.</dd>
 
  <dt>*.ma</dt>
  <dd>KAG area action definition files.</dd>
 

</dl>
</para>

</doc>