<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>Prerendered Font Data Creation Tool</title>

<para>
<ptitle>About the Prerendered Font Data Creation Tool</ptitle>
 The Prerendered Font Data Creation Tool is a tool for creating <kw>prerendered font</kw> data. This data can be assigned to actual fonts using <at href="f_Font_mapPrerenderedFont.html">Font.mapPrerenderedFont</at>.<r/>
 "Prerendered" means that the font has been rendered in advance (in this case, expanding TrueType outline fonts and converting them into bitmap fonts). If you do not use this, KiriKiri will perform rendering at runtime as needed.<r/>
 Since prerendered fonts are created in the creator's environment, using them allows the same font to be used regardless of the player's environment.<r/>
 Prerendered font data is bitmap font data. In other words, unlike TrueType, it is not scalable (the size cannot be changed freely), so one font file handles only one fixed font size.<r/>
<note>
 If it is unclear whether the author of the original font you are trying to create prerendered font data from permits the font to be used for such purposes (distributing bitmap data of many characters created from that font along with a game, etc., and combining that bitmap data for character display), we recommend checking with the font's author.<r/>
 By the way, this prerendered font file is in KiriKiri's own format, and there is almost no possibility of it being used for other purposes.<r/>
 The author of KiriKiri is not concerned with any problems that may occur using this software.<r/>
</note>
<r/>
 This tool relies heavily on the OS's UNICODE support, so it will not work on Windows 95. It works on Windows 98/98SE/ME and Windows NT 4.0, but some functions are limited. All functions can be used on Windows 2000/XP.<r/>
 Of course, the restrictions based on the type of OS apply to the environment where this font is created; the type of OS on the side that uses the prerendered font data created with this tool does not matter.<r/>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>How to use the Prerendered Font Data Creation Tool</ptitle>
<img src="FontMaker.png"/><r/><r/>
 When you run the Prerendered Font Data Creation Tool (krkrfont.exe in the tools folder), the screen above is displayed.<r/>
<r/>
<dl>
<dt>"Font Name"</dt>
<dd>
 Specifies the name of the font that will be the source for creating the prerendered font data. If you want to create a font for vertical writing, select a font with an @ mark at the beginning.
</dd>

<dt>"Show all TrueType fonts"</dt>
<dd>
 If not checked, only fonts whose character type is Japanese will be listed in "Font Name", but if checked, all TrueType fonts will be displayed.
</dd>

<dt>"Size (Character Height)"</dt>
<dd>
 Specifies the size (character height) of the prerendered font to be created in pixels.
</dd>

<dt>"Anti-aliasing"</dt>
<dd>
 Specifies whether to perform anti-aliasing. Anti-aliasing makes the font smoother.
</dd>

<dt>"Bold"</dt>
<dd>
 Specifies whether to make it bold. This can only be checked on Windows NT-based OS (NT4, 2000, XP, Vista, 7, etc.).
</dd>

<dt>"Include all characters in font"</dt>
<dd>
 Specifies whether to include all characters present in the font. This can only be checked on Windows NT-based OS (excluding NT4).<r/>
 If checked, all characters included in the font will be output.<r/>
 If not checked, only characters corresponding to Shift JIS and half-width alphanumeric/kana will be output.<r/>
<note>
 The behavior when not checked depends on the locale in which this tool is running. Normally, when running on Japanese Windows, it means that only characters corresponding to Shift JIS, etc., will be output. (Though the author does not know because they do not have anything other than Japanese Windows)<r/>
</note>
</dd>

<dt>"Include user-defined characters"</dt>
<dd>
 Specifies whether to include user-defined characters (Gaiji). This can only be selected on Windows NT-based OS (excluding NT4). On other OS, it will always be checked.<r/>
 User-defined characters can be created with the "Private Character Editor" included with Windows.
</dd>

<dt>"Sample"</dt>
<dd>
 Displays a sample of the prerendered font created with the selected conditions. In this "Sample", you can check all the characters that will be output.
</dd>

<dt>"Output File"</dt>
<dd>
 Specifies the file to be output. The extension of the output file will be .tft. Clicking "Browse" allows you to specify the file in a dialog box.
</dd>

<dt>"Create"</dt>
<dd>
 Creates the prerendered font file.
</dd>

<dt>"Close"</dt>
<dd>
 Exits this tool.
</dd>
</dl>
</para>


</doc>