<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>Releaser</title>

<para>
<ptitle>About Releaser</ptitle>
 Releaser is a tool for bundling folders into archive files.<r/>
 Additionally, by specifying a KiriKiri project folder, you can create a single executable file that contains the project folder internally.<r/>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>How to use Releaser</ptitle>
<img src="ReleaserSelect.png"/><r/><r/>
 When you run Releaser (krkrrel.exe in the tools folder), you will first be asked to specify a folder. Please select the folder.<r/>
 The files inside the specified folder will be targeted.<r/>
<r/>
<note>
 Releaser has a feature where, during the process of creating the final archive, if it finds files with identical content, it will bundle them together even if the filenames are different, using only the capacity of a single file.
</note>
<note>
 Releaser automatically ignores CVS meta-information directories (directories named "CVS" containing a file named "Repository"). It also ignores files and directories whose names start with a . (dot) (such as UNIX-style hidden files or Subversion meta-information directories).
</note>
<note>
 When Releaser creates an archive, it creates a file named <kw>default.rpf</kw> in the directory where the archive was created. This file contains the options used during archive creation, allowing you to easily create archives with the same settings next time.
</note>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>Releaser Settings Screen</ptitle>
 After selecting a folder, the settings screen will appear.<r/>
<dl>
<dt>"Return to Folder Selection" button</dt>
<dd>
 Allows you to restart the folder selection process.
</dd>

<dt>"Profile: Save" button</dt>
<dd>
 Saves the current settings to a file.
</dd>

<dt>"Profile: Load" button</dt>
<dd>
 Loads settings from a file.
</dd>

<dt>"Create" button</dt>
<dd>
 Outputs an archive file or an EXE format executable based on the current settings.
</dd>

<dt>"Cancel" (or Exit) button</dt>
<dd>
 Exits Releaser.
</dd>

<dt>"Output" tab</dt>
<dd>
<img src="ReleaserOutput.png"/><r/><r/>
<dl>
<dt>"Output Format"</dt>
<dd>
 Selecting ".XP3 Archive" outputs a file in xp3 format (the standard KiriKiri archive format). Selecting ".EXE Executable" outputs an executable file. If ".EXE Executable" is selected, the krkr.eXe located in the same folder as Releaser (krkrrel.exe) or its parent folder will be used.
</dd>

<dt>"Output File"</dt>
<dd>
 Specify the file to be output. Clicking the "Browse" button allows you to specify the file via a dialog box.
</dd>
</dl>
</dd>

<dt>"Files" tab</dt>
<dd>
<img src="ReleaserFiles.png"/><r/><r/>
 For each extension, you can choose "Compress", "Include in archive but do not compress", or "Do not include in archive". Usually, the default classification is fine.<r/>
 Classifying files as "Compress" will perform compression, reducing the file size. Additionally, it makes the content difficult to decipher when viewed with a text or binary editor. However, compression has the disadvantage of taking time during extraction. Since formats like PNG, JPEG, and ERI are already compressed, classifying them as "Compress" yields little benefit and increases extraction time, so compression is not recommended for them.
</dd>

<dt>"Options" tab</dt>
<dd>
<img src="ReleaserSettings.png"/><r/><r/>
<dl>
<dt>"Do not compress large files"</dt>
<dd>
 Even if a file is classified as "Compress", this setting prevents compression if the file exceeds the specified size. Due to KiriKiri's structure, compressed files must be expanded in memory, so compressing large files results in high runtime costs.
</dd>

<dt>"Extraction Protect"</dt>
<dd>
 When checked, the "Extraction Protect" attribute is added to the index (the list of stored files) inside the archive. This allows you to signal to archive extraction tools that "the author does not wish for the files to be extracted".
</dd>

<dt>"OggVorbis Codebook Sharing"</dt>
<dd>
 When checked, the vector quantization codebooks for OggVorbis files (.ogg files) are shared. Since OggVorbis files often contain common codebooks across multiple files, bundling them into one can save space.
</dd>

<dt>"Compress Index"</dt>
<dd>
 When checked, the index inside the archive (the list of stored files) is compressed to save space.
</dd>
</dl>
<note>
Checking "Extraction Protect" in the "Options" tab <b>does not actually perform encryption to prevent extraction</b>. It only serves as a declaration of intent. Also, those who create archive extraction tools (if any) should take the existence of this extraction protect flag into account (e.g., by refusing extraction or showing a warning before extracting if this flag is set).<r/>
</note>
</dd>

<dt>"Executable Settings" tab</dt>
<dd>
 This is displayed only when an executable file is specified as the output format.<r/>
 The settings screen here is the same as in <link href="Configure"/>.<r/>
<r/>
<img src="ReleaserExeSettings.png"/><r/><r/>
<dl>
<dt>"Options"</dt>
<dd>
 You can set the default options for the executable file.
</dd>

<dt>"Icon"</dt>
<dd>
 You can specify the icon for the executable file.
</dd>
</dl>
</dd>
</dl>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>Command Line Options</ptitle>
Releaser accepts the following command line options.

<dl>

<dt>Folder name</dt>
<dd>Specifies the target folder.</dd>

<dt>-<kw>go</kw></dt>
<dd>Creates the archive immediately and then exits. Use this for batch processing, etc. Please save the options in advance as default.rpf in the target folder (even without this, it is possible to create an archive by combining it with the -nowriterpf and -out options).</dd>

<dt>-nowriterpf</dt>
<dd>Does not write default.rpf upon exit.</dd>

<dt>-out filename</dt>
<dd>Specifies the output filename.</dd>

<dt>-rpf filename</dt>
<dd>Specifies the profile to load.</dd>

</dl>
<r/>
For example, specify as follows.<r/>
<bq>
krkrrel project -out ..\release\data.xp3 -nowriterpf -go
</bq>

</para>

</doc>