<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<doc>
<title>Storage System</title>

<para>
<ptitle>About the Storage System</ptitle>
 In KiriKiri, files, files within archives, and other resources are intentionally called "storages" rather than just files.<r/>
</para>


<para>
<ptitle>Unified Storage Name</ptitle>
 A Unified Storage Name is a name used to represent a storage only within KiriKiri, using a method similar to a URI.<r/>
 The notation is as follows:<r/>
<r/>
<tt>media://domain/path</tt><r/>
<r/>
 It is written in this format. The path delimiter is / (slash).<r/>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>Local Storage</ptitle>
 The Unified Storage Name for local storage (local files) uses "file" for the media and "." (dot) for the domain. In Windows, the beginning of the path is the drive letter.<r/>
<r/>
 For example, C:\Program Files\Game\game.exe becomes:<r/>
<tt>file://./c/program files/game/game.exe</tt><r/>
 .<r/>
<r/>
 The <at href="f_Storages_getFullPath.html">Storages.getFullPath</at> method can convert a filename used by the OS into a Unified Storage Name. During this process, all uppercase letters in the filename are converted to lowercase (local storage is case-insensitive). Also, if \ is used as a path delimiter, it is converted to /.<r/>
 The <at href="f_Storages_getLocalName.html">Storages.getLocalName</at> method can convert a Unified Storage Name into a filename used by the OS. This method must be used when passing storage names to applications other than KiriKiri.<r/>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>Archive Storage</ptitle>
 To specify a storage within an archive, use &gt; as a delimiter, where the part before &gt; is the storage name of the archive storage, and the part after &gt; is the path within the archive.<r/>
<r/>
 For example, for a storage named image/base.jpg inside file://./c/program files/game/game.xp3, it would be:<r/>
<tt>file://./c/program files/game/game.xp3&gt;image/base.jpg</tt><r/>
 .<r/>
 Since 2.19 beta 14, the archive delimiter has changed from '#' to '&gt;'.<r/>
<r/>
 KiriKiri can handle XP3, a proprietary archive storage format, by default (XP3 stands for the 3rd generation of the XPK format). Please refer to <link href="Releaser"/> for instructions on how to create XP3 format archives.<r/>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>Project Folder</ptitle>
 When creating games or tools with KiriKiri, it is common practice to organize all necessary files into a "Project Folder" for development. KiriKiri sets the project folder as the current folder upon startup.<r/>
 If everything is specified using relative paths within the project folder, there is no need to change path specifications even if you use the Releaser to create a single executable file.<r/>
</para>

<para>
<ptitle>Data Storage Location</ptitle>
 The data storage location is the folder specified by the -datapath option in <link href="CommandLine" />. It can be retrieved using the <at href="f_System_dataPath.html">System.dataPath</at> property.<r/>
 Various logs output by KiriKiri and user-specific configuration files are output here.<r/>
 Additionally, when users create games or tools, it is recommended to save data here.<r/>
</para>


</doc>